<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>unity - Geraldo Nascimento</title><description>Creative Game Making</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><generator>Ghost 0.7</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 12:05:29 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/tag/unity/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>Dev Blog #5 - Steam Greenlight and the Journey to Kickstarter</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I bring you fantastic, joyful news. &lt;strong&gt;Gunkatana&lt;/strong&gt; has been &lt;a href="http://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=637591816"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Greenlit&lt;/strong&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;Steam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; after less than two weeks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am ecstatic. Everyone on the team is really happy. But there's more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past day, more than &lt;strong&gt;700 people&lt;/strong&gt; have downloaded the &lt;a href="http://gamejolt.com/games/gunkatana/133872"&gt;pre-alpha build from &lt;strong&gt;GameJolt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, after we landed on the&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/dev-blog-5-the-journey-to-steam-greenlight/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">babbf024-3474-48fb-a8d5-0c5bf0404321</guid><category>gunkatana</category><category>unity</category><category>devblog</category><category>indiedev</category><category>gamedev</category><dc:creator>Geraldo Nascimento</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 20:58:16 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/05/thankyou.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/05/thankyou.png" alt="Dev Blog #5 - Steam Greenlight and the Journey to Kickstarter"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I bring you fantastic, joyful news. &lt;strong&gt;Gunkatana&lt;/strong&gt; has been &lt;a href="http://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=637591816"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Greenlit&lt;/strong&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;Steam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; after less than two weeks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am ecstatic. Everyone on the team is really happy. But there's more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past day, more than &lt;strong&gt;700 people&lt;/strong&gt; have downloaded the &lt;a href="http://gamejolt.com/games/gunkatana/133872"&gt;pre-alpha build from &lt;strong&gt;GameJolt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, after we landed on the first page as a &lt;strong&gt;GameJolt featured&lt;/strong&gt; game!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From that, we've already spotted two &lt;strong&gt;Youtuber&lt;/strong&gt; Let's Play videos of Gunkatana:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/maNcEH_LmPI" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MegaGWolf's&lt;/strong&gt; take on the game is very positive and wonderful to hear. Watching as he discovers the mechanics of the game and really gets a blast of fun out of it, it's the reason we are doing this in the first place! BTW it was his idea to show that particular cyborg ninja on the thumbnail :p&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm making a note here: I'm really &lt;strong&gt;happy about this&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then we have &lt;strong&gt;l'academie du noob&lt;/strong&gt;'s &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8-DwbE3zTfI"&gt;gameplay video&lt;/a&gt; in French. His feedback is also very positive, and points out all the things we know we must improve: better AI, and more modes, levels - it's all in the pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very soon we are going to be launching a &lt;strong&gt;Kickstarter&lt;/strong&gt; campaign. We've been preparing it for the past few months, and we've got a wealth of things to show that we haven't yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;pre-alpha build&lt;/strong&gt;; getting on &lt;strong&gt;Steam Greenlight&lt;/strong&gt;; they were our initial move - let's get this out there and see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Gunkatana already &lt;strong&gt;Greenlit&lt;/strong&gt; going into the &lt;strong&gt;Kickstarter&lt;/strong&gt; and extremely positive feedback from players, we are very confident, but we need your help!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We've done a ton of work on &lt;strong&gt;Gunkatana&lt;/strong&gt;'s official website - I'm incredibly proud of the work &lt;strong&gt;João Nascimento&lt;/strong&gt; (not my brother, but one of my best friends!) has put into making our home on the web a place filled with all the information you need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check it out here: &lt;a href="http://gunkatana.com"&gt;www.gunkatana.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sign up there to get the latest updates on &lt;strong&gt;Gunkatana&lt;/strong&gt;. If you like what you're seeing, we hope you'll like what's coming next!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to give a shoutout to all the members of &lt;strong&gt;Team Gunkatana&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CrazyArcadia&lt;/strong&gt; - for his continuous hard work on making the best pixel art, coming up with game design ideas off the cuff and discussing them on the fly, making the gorgeous &lt;strong&gt;THANK YOU GREENLIGHT COMMUNITY&lt;/strong&gt; artwork we have posted everywhere now, and for being a &lt;strong&gt;freakin' BADASS&lt;/strong&gt; - he made the city landscape flyover animation you see on the trailer in an incredibly short time!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;João Nascimento&lt;/strong&gt; - for crafting a fantastic website - and updating it on the fly, being available at all times, hitting us with his own perspective on the game, being someone me and everyone else on the team can always count on, his behind-the-scenes work on getting all the stuff we've shown so far - like getting all the &lt;a href="http://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=637591816"&gt;Steam Greenlight&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://torn-page.itch.io/gunkatana"&gt;itch.io&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.indiedb.com/games/gunkatana"&gt;IndieDB&lt;/a&gt; pages ready and helping out with the forum posts, and for being The Wrath!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sarah Schemske&lt;/strong&gt; - for creating with us a wonderful cyberpunk world we are very eager to explore, for adding depth to the story and triple-checking all the text we put out there (and for correcting the grammar!), and for coming up with fantastic ideas we can't wait to tell you about! You should read her atmospheric short stories set in the world of Gunkatana &lt;a href="http://gunkatana.com/chronicles.html"&gt;at our site&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thank &lt;strong&gt;Joonas Turner&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Niilo Takalainen&lt;/strong&gt; for the brutal sound design we have on the pre-alpha build already. Can't wait to get them to make more crunchy sounds! A big thanks also to &lt;strong&gt;Miriam Grohmann&lt;/strong&gt; for creating the trailer after me and &lt;strong&gt;João&lt;/strong&gt; tried our hand at it - and ending up in pain (Adobe Premiere is much harder than we tought)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to thank &lt;strong&gt;Electric Cafe&lt;/strong&gt; as well for the retrowave pumping music they keep making for the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can check out a sample here:  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="100%" height="450" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/251325722&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You haven't seen any of &lt;strong&gt;Marco Machado&lt;/strong&gt;'s art for the game yet, but you won't have to wait much longer. Really looking forward to unleashing it all on you very soon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you all for your support and look out for our &lt;strong&gt;Kickstarter&lt;/strong&gt; coming soon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Follow Gunkatana on&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=637591816"&gt;Steam Greenlight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gamejolt.com/games/gunkatana/133872"&gt;GameJolt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gunkatana.com"&gt;Official Site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Dev Blog #4 - The Gunkatana Team</title><description>Who are the people behind Gunkatana?</description><link>http://localhost:2368/dev-blog-4-the-journey-to-steam-greenlight/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">ba618f79-ffd0-4160-a36d-694a97343915</guid><category>gunkatana</category><category>unity</category><category>devblog</category><category>indiedev</category><category>gamedev</category><dc:creator>Geraldo Nascimento</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 11:12:43 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/03/socmed_banner.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;iframe width="420" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FvmepmQxYAE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/03/socmed_banner.png" alt="Dev Blog #4 - The Gunkatana Team"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gunkatana is my game in development, a celebration of style and bloodshed. "Easy to learn, hard to master" &lt;strong&gt;zero-sum combat&lt;/strong&gt; with laser guns, swords, and our unique &lt;em&gt;TURBO-RAILS&lt;/em&gt;, an ultraviolent take on skateboard &lt;strong&gt;grinding&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="theteam"&gt;THE TEAM&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, now that you know what &lt;strong&gt;Gunkatana&lt;/strong&gt; is, who the hell is making it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me? I'm &lt;strong&gt;Geraldo&lt;/strong&gt;, a game programmer from Portugal. I moved to the UK almost 4 years ago to follow my passion for these things we call video games, and in 2014 I created a prototype that eventually became &lt;strong&gt;Gunkatana&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this game, I'm inspired by movies like &lt;strong&gt;The Matrix&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Kill Bill&lt;/strong&gt; and by games like &lt;strong&gt;Hotline Miami&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Grand Theft Auto&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Towerfall&lt;/strong&gt;. I relish on satisfying combat mechanics, the &lt;em&gt;weighty feel&lt;/em&gt; of attacks and movements, and putting that into the game &lt;em&gt;has been a joy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most difficult part for me, but perhaps the most satisfying as well, is the disconnect between what I want to add to the game, and how well what's in my mind translates into the finished project. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Toying around prototyping new combat and movement mechanics is something that really satisfies me, probably more so than adding "content".&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second most difficult part comes from my career development, as I spent most of my time as a software engineer, solving problems, developing an incredibly useful array of skills for game making. But that came at the cost of not developing my creativity, at least in terms of making things and putting them out there for everyone to see (any software engineer / programmer will tell you that it requires a LOT of creativity, and I don't deny it!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So sometimes I struggle with going on with the project, considering if what I am doing is really worth doing at all, if it is worth bothering other people with. I'm sure everyone feels this as well, at a certain amount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, here we are, Gunkatana is on Steam Greenlight waiting for your votes, we've got a fantastic trailer (with the help of Miriam Ghromann) and our first playable build is out for people to check it out from the comfort of their homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially a project solely by me and &lt;strong&gt;CrazyArcadia&lt;/strong&gt;, we've since expanded the team: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sarah Schemske&lt;/strong&gt; is the project's writer, and she's fleshing out the personalities of our playable characters and the dystopian world where the game is set; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;João Nascimento&lt;/strong&gt; is our producer, which means he makes sure everything is on track, helps us get the game out into the open, and motivates us (it's no wonder we've nicknamed him &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wrath&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;);&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marco Machado&lt;/strong&gt;, artist, is creating something beautiful that we will be revealing in the coming weeks;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joonas Turner&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Niilo Takalainen&lt;/strong&gt;, the sound designers behind Broforce, are crafting every katana slash and laser shot spark, and have also given us the first voice of Gunkatana in the form of our sarcastic in-game announcer;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Electric Cafe&lt;/strong&gt;, the people behind Aqua Kitty and Rock Boshers retro soundtracks, are creating a retrowave soundtrack for the game, that you can already hear in our playable demo and in available samples at their Soundcloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wouldn't be here, working full time on this project, if it wasn't for them, and other friends who have helped us get it this far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Support us on &lt;a href="http://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=637591816"&gt;Steam Greenlight&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://torn-page.itch.io/gunkatana"&gt;Download the pre-alpha build&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Dev Blog #2 - Intel Developer Showcase Winner</title><description>Showcased at the Intel Buzz Workshop event, Gunkatana was voted by the attendees as the best game on show. Gunkatana: lightning fast cyberpunk action!</description><link>http://localhost:2368/gunkatana-developer-showcase-winner/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">8f2a6650-b280-44a2-9ea5-36f0e7a14a24</guid><category>gunkatana</category><category>unity</category><category>devblog</category><category>indiedev</category><category>gamedev</category><dc:creator>Geraldo Nascimento</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 16:27:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2015/12/Screen-Shot-2015-11-26-at-11-02-49-1.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2015/12/Screen-Shot-2015-11-26-at-11-02-49-1.png" alt="Dev Blog #2 - Intel Developer Showcase Winner"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Intel and BeMyApp hosted the &lt;a href="https://software.intel.com/en-us/event/buzzworkshop"&gt;Intel Buzz Workshop&lt;/a&gt; event on December 8th, where a cadre of games industry experts gave talks and panels on a number of really interesting subjects, like game design, how to make your own game engine and VR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2015/12/Solivagant_2015-Dec-08-1.jpg" alt="Dev Blog #2 - Intel Developer Showcase Winner" style="width: 600px;  display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed The Future of Indie Games panel hosted by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/oh_cripes"&gt;Joe Bain&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/attilioHimeki"&gt;Attilio Carotenuto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/usefulslug"&gt;Vegard Myklebust&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/gormlai"&gt;Gorm Lai&lt;/a&gt;, all great, proficient game devs and friends I’ve met in the London indie dev community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My biggest takeaway was Gorm’s insistence: &lt;strong&gt;“polish, polish, polish!”&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I definitely agree, it’s what I’m working on with &lt;strong&gt;Gunkatana&lt;/strong&gt;, polishing the hell out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event had a special &lt;strong&gt;Developer Showcase&lt;/strong&gt;, a challenge open to any indie developers, studios or students. I submitted &lt;strong&gt;Gunkatana&lt;/strong&gt; and was thankfully accepted to the participate, along with 7 other games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My day consisted of manning the Gunkatana table, explaining the game to attendees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The joy in seeing someone pick the game up and really quickly &lt;em&gt;get it&lt;/em&gt;, understand what it’s all about and join in the banter, this is the reason why I’ve quit my previous job and gone &lt;strong&gt;full time&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing someone take real fun from something I’ve built and designed is an &lt;em&gt;incredible happy feeling&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2015/12/BeMyAppUK_2015-Dec-08-1.jpg" alt="Dev Blog #2 - Intel Developer Showcase Winner" style="width: 480px;  display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"&gt; &lt;br&gt;
The &lt;strong&gt;Developer Showcase&lt;/strong&gt; urged attendees to vote on the Best Game of the Show, and &lt;strong&gt;Gunkatana won!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This marks the first award Gunkatana has received, and I’m pretty sure it won’t be the last!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2015/12/Solivagant_2015-Dec-08.jpg" alt="Dev Blog #2 - Intel Developer Showcase Winner" style="width: 480px;  display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People really enjoyed playing it and picked up on the text we’ve placed on the game when you kill someone: &lt;em&gt;“Selfie Kill”&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;“Rail Kill”&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;“SWIPED!”&lt;/em&gt;, and some would even say it out loud. The same happened at GameCity!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the expressions and words people told me throughout the day:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“this is amazing” 
“this is so cool” 
“it feels really good” 
“controls very well” 
“satisfying to kill the other characters”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I turned on the very &lt;strong&gt;prototypical&lt;/strong&gt; AI bots on some occasions, and players would keep killing them and enjoying that interaction, despite the AI bots still being a bit embrionary and not being able to use all the weapons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gunkatana is a very fast paced action game that features a number of very quick game mechanics. Once you get what makes it tick, you can quickly &lt;strong&gt;zip around the arena&lt;/strong&gt; and destroy your enemies, making cool &lt;strong&gt;reflected laser&lt;/strong&gt; kills and &lt;strong&gt;running&lt;/strong&gt; them over!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2015/12/Turbo.gif" alt="Dev Blog #2 - Intel Developer Showcase Winner"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m so used to the game that I kept accidentally slaying the other players without even realising, so by the end of the day I just watched people play rather than join in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the many takeaways I got is that there’s room to introduce the mechanics piece by piece so that players get used to them. That isn’t very easy to do on a pure local multiplayer game, which gives me more fuel to develop the &lt;strong&gt;single player / co-op campaign&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also want to give players a good package of fun, since the game feel and mechanics are so enjoyable, I want to give them a chance to practice their skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was also the first time that I had people try out the new respawning feature, and despite a bug here and there, it worked pretty well, and players understood &lt;strong&gt;they could choose where and when to respawn&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One suggestion I took to heart to &lt;strong&gt;signal a character's death&lt;/strong&gt; more, so they're aware they  have died. Which means researching other games to figure out how best to do it, besides, you know, splattering the corpse all over the place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a fantastic day, as all days that I have shown the game at an event are, really!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2015/12/Explosion.gif" alt="Dev Blog #2 - Intel Developer Showcase Winner"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re now preparing to put the game on &lt;strong&gt;Greenlight&lt;/strong&gt;, and hoping to &lt;strong&gt;release the game early next year&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow dev updates on my &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/solivagant"&gt;@Solivagant&lt;/a&gt; twitter account!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out &lt;a href="http://gunkatana.com"&gt;www.Gunkatana.com&lt;/a&gt; for in-game lore and screenshots!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Dev Blog #1 - Origins of Gunkatana</title><description>This is how Gunkatana got started, the local multiplayer / single player &amp; coop top down retro action game driving a katana into your soul. First dev blog.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/the-origins-of-gunkatana/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">8d6ee96a-b75e-436c-9123-4978dbc982fe</guid><category>gunkatana</category><category>unity</category><category>devblog</category><dc:creator>Geraldo Nascimento</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 11:34:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2015/11/Origins-of-Gunkatana.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2015/11/Origins-of-Gunkatana.png" alt="Dev Blog #1 - Origins of Gunkatana"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since last year I've been having a lot of conversations that start with someone asking me a specific question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"So what's your game about?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Cyberpunk, lasers, katanas, turbo grind rails &amp;amp; lots of &lt;strong&gt;juice&lt;/strong&gt;."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2015/11/Gunkatana---Revolt-of-the-AI.gif" alt="Dev Blog #1 - Origins of Gunkatana"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's how I introduce &lt;strong&gt;Gunkatana&lt;/strong&gt;, the game I'm now developing as a full time indie developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gunkatana&lt;/strong&gt; was born from a confluence of two events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="birth"&gt;BIRTH&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/londongamespace"&gt;London Game Space&lt;/a&gt; hosted an event to showcase locally sourced &lt;strong&gt;local multiplayer games&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had never shown a game to anyone and have them play it and critique it before. I was just starting to get my feet wet developing prototypes in &lt;strong&gt;Unity&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tinkered with a very early top down action game I was working on and tacked a second player on it. Challenged myself to go ahead and show that game at the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I developed that first draft of &lt;strong&gt;Gunkatana&lt;/strong&gt; as an attempt to decipher what made &lt;a href="http://hotlinemiami.com"&gt;Hotline Miami&lt;/a&gt; tick. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watching Hotline Miami's sequel trailer was the second pivotal event. It has inspired me in those initial game dev hours and ever since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The feedback I got from that initial demo was great. It was already somewhat fun, if incredibly basic and unpolished. Players gave me tons of ideas of where to take it next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The core gameplay was already there: &lt;strong&gt;lasers&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;turbo speed grind rails&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="speedkills"&gt;SPEED KILLS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The speed rails started off as quick way to implement the Matrix's wall running. I wanted to create a game with that sense of speed and action, letting you speed along the walls, Mirror's Edge like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2015/11/Old-Days.gif" alt="Dev Blog #1 - Origins of Gunkatana" style="width: 480px;  display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually I started laying the speed tracks anywhere in the level, and they became speed rails on the floor. The Gunkatana fighters attach their boots to them and zoom along the rails at high speeds, running over whoever's on the way, corpses thrown about and blood flying everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/burningsushi"&gt;Sujan&lt;/a&gt;, one of the great friends I’ve made at the London Indies scene, told me to actually implement the titular sword from the title. I did so. It's really fun to be writing C# classes called &lt;em&gt;KatanaDashSlash&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="fromnothingeverything"&gt;FROM NOTHING, EVERYTHING&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I needed someone to bring the world of Gunkatana to life, and put out a call for artists on Twitter. A friend, Florian, recommended me one of his friends and thus I met &lt;a href="http://localhost:2368/the-origins-of-gunkatana/www.crazyarcadia.com"&gt;CrazyArcadia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CrazyArcadia knocked out a beautiful mockup, and I was in love with those pixels. It's always fascinating for me to suddenly see imagination becoming reality. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The core of Gunkatana is a competitive mix of dark futuristic themes and very mechanically tight gameplay, infused with combat from The Matrix and Equilibrium. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing it come to life from my initial programmer art &amp;amp; OpenGameArt assets into something palpable, phosphorous &amp;amp; vibrant, it's an incredible experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both me and CrazyArcadia are responsible for the game design and its a joy to discuss gameplay mechanics and level designs with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result is what you see in this preliminary trailer, featuring original music by &lt;a href="http://www.electriccafe.xyz"&gt;Electric Cafe&lt;/a&gt; of Aqua Kitty soundtrack fame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4F2avVTbuAY" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id="future"&gt;FUTURE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gunkatana was born from participating in the London indie dev community. The feedback I get when showing it and playing it at events has been invaluable and has helped shape where it's now, and will help shape where it's headed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2015/11/GameCity2015-Stand.jpg" alt="Dev Blog #1 - Origins of Gunkatana"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Our stand at GameCity 2015, a volunteer driven games event at Nottingham, UK&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gunkatana has received very positive press coverage, at &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2015/nov/02/gamecity-2015"&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.impactnottingham.com/2015/11/gamecity-gunkatana/"&gt;Impact Nottingham&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm incredibly proud of what we've achieved so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2015/11/BeefyGif.gif" alt="Dev Blog #1 - Origins of Gunkatana"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tying together the efforts of &lt;a href="http://localhost:2368/the-origins-of-gunkatana/www.crazyarcadia.com"&gt;CrazyArcadia&lt;/a&gt;, lead artist and game designer on the project, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/LesenistGold"&gt;Sarah Schemske&lt;/a&gt;, writer for Gunkatana, &lt;a href="http://www.crowsmos.pt"&gt;João Nascimento&lt;/a&gt;, website designer, &lt;a href="http://davidanstey.com"&gt;David Anstey&lt;/a&gt;, who designed one of our main characters, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/eccentricsheep"&gt;Nell F.&lt;/a&gt;, who designed the wonderful poster art, &lt;a href="http://www.electriccafe.xyz"&gt;Electric Cafe&lt;/a&gt;'s music, while simultaneously adding new &lt;strong&gt;features&lt;/strong&gt;, level &lt;strong&gt;building&lt;/strong&gt; techniques, &lt;strong&gt;quality of life&lt;/strong&gt; software engineering practices and just fun stuff like &lt;strong&gt;running over your enemies when grinding the rails&lt;/strong&gt;, makes me incredibly happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gunkatana is due for release in the first half of 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.gunkatana.com"&gt;www.gunkatana.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>