<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>juice - Geraldo Nascimento</title><description>Creative Game Making</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><generator>Ghost 0.7</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 12:05:29 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/tag/juice/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>DEV BLOG #3 - DRINK YOUR JUICE</title><description>Game Juice is that ethereal quality that makes a game pop and go beyond mere interactivity into something that crackles, fizzes, squishes and breathes.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/dev-blog-3-drink-your-juice/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">cad22ada-7659-4aba-9ac0-eedc073987f6</guid><category>gunkatana</category><category>devblog</category><category>gamedev</category><category>juice</category><dc:creator>Geraldo Nascimento</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 22:10:23 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/01/tumblr_n9t48f9YCj1ti5owoo2_r5_500.gif" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/01/tumblr_n9t48f9YCj1ti5owoo2_r5_500.gif" alt="DEV BLOG #3 - DRINK YOUR JUICE"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Juice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is that ethereal quality that makes a game &lt;strong&gt;pop&lt;/strong&gt; and go beyond mere interactivity into something that &lt;em&gt;crackles&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;fizzes&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;mark&gt;squishes&lt;/mark&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;breathes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/01/Solivagant_2016-Jan-24.gif" alt="DEV BLOG #3 - DRINK YOUR JUICE" title=""&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Osman (Mitchell Corporation - arcade - 1996)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grapefrukt&lt;/strong&gt;'s talk Juice It Or Lose It is the absolute textbook lesson on all things game juice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Fy0aCDmgnxg" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've become fascinated the concept of game juice and I see it now in movies, flashing animations, adverts, TV shows. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's &lt;strong&gt;like seeing The Matrix&lt;/strong&gt;, and I'm now a really big proponent of it, striving to raise #gamedevs' awareness of Juice and learning when to apply it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think of game juice not just as subtly tweening  of game elements, but as the various components of animated and interactive content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've been collecting the best examples of game juice for my inspiration and entertainment, and I want to share what I've been collecting, hoping to give other &lt;strong&gt;#gamedevs&lt;/strong&gt; the chance to come up with their own juicy creations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than just serving as a gorgeous gif gallery, I want to break down the juicy components of each example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="juicesample1rtypeleo"&gt;JUICE SAMPLE #1 - R-TYPE LEO&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/01/tumblr_o17jtkAFZd1u6jjy9o1_400.gif" alt="DEV BLOG #3 - DRINK YOUR JUICE"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love this bouncy laser weapon in R-Type Leo, as well as should, cause &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gunkatana&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the game I'm developing full time, features bouncing lasers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's fast &lt;strong&gt;flashing red&lt;/strong&gt; circles, which didn't need to be there, but they increase the intensity of the piece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the lasers hit the enemies there's a &lt;strong&gt;white red flash&lt;/strong&gt; and an explosion. On the walls, the bombs create a similar, though smaller, explosive effect, while the lasers firing directly ahead of the ship create a blue and white explosion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And all of that in such a short gif!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id="juicesample2towerfall"&gt;JUICE SAMPLE #2 - TOWERFALL&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/01/Towerfall-Double-Kill.gif" alt="DEV BLOG #3 - DRINK YOUR JUICE"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Towerfall is a great example of a modern indie game that's really in touch with juice. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the characters jump they're sort of squeezed, their shape is tweened, the same when they're dashing. It's a really interesting way of making the most out of a sprite animation by tweaking it in code and creating a cartoonish animated style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The arrows have a light on the background, the torches are animated and there's snow in the background, all working together to form a very dynamic level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is one of the challenges we are facing developing &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gunkatana&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. As a top down game, we need to think of ways of making the floors and the various elements of the level interesting to look at from that perspective. It's not as easy as just going for a parallax effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the 3rd Dev Blog for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gunkatana&lt;/em&gt;, the lightning-fast cyberpunk ACTION game&lt;/strong&gt; I'm developing as a full time indie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read up on Gunkatana's development story!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://geraldonascimento.ghost.io/gunkatana-developer-showcase-winner/"&gt;Dev Blog #2 - Intel Developer Showcase Winner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://geraldonascimento.ghost.io/the-origins-of-gunkatana/"&gt;Dev Blog #1 - The Origins of Gunkatana&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>