<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>personal - Geraldo Nascimento</title><description>Creative Game Making</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><generator>Ghost 0.7</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 12:05:29 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/tag/personal/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>The Creative Process</title><description>Fostering a creative process takes time. Look to your inspirations deep enough and you'll find the cracks where glue ws applied. </description><link>http://localhost:2368/creativity/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">e9d1fa25-aa8b-4eaf-9472-fd32d7cbe1c5</guid><category>personal</category><category>creativity</category><dc:creator>Geraldo Nascimento</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2015/10/stealBook.jpg" alt="alt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Creativity&lt;/em&gt; is reinterpreting what comes inside you into something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;strong&gt;struggled&lt;/strong&gt; for years to come up with something original. That affected my craft, to the point where I didn't consider anything I did original enough; I would stop myself before it started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I prototyped some ideas, stumbled my way, but when seeing similarities between what I was building and other games, I’d falter, craving to build something wholly original, from the root, and failing to muster the &lt;em&gt;creativity&lt;/em&gt; to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That all changed once I read &lt;a href="http://austinkleon.com/steal/" title="Steal like an Artist"&gt;Steal Like an Artist&lt;/a&gt; by Austin Kleon while on a flight. I bought it by chance on the airport's shops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without access to the internet or a computer, I took notes of what I learned from the book, and my mind was ablaze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How I approach &lt;strong&gt;creativity&lt;/strong&gt; has completely changed since then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artists by education will already have a grasp of this, but for the budding software coder or game designer that is getting in touch with their creativity, the concept of stealing and copying, in order to come up with their own ideas, could seem wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; have involuntarily practiced premature self-rejection when writing and concepting, for years. I'd sabotage myself and wouldn't break through, thinking that comparing what I was making with something else was wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THIS&lt;/strong&gt; is the message I want to get across: don’t stifle your creative process by outright rejecting your early ideas. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Write down your derivative ideas!&lt;/strong&gt; Let them percolate in your mind, and then enrich them, mix them, change them, make them your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t advocate that it's ok for games like 2048 to spring up, just cloning a game’s mechanics heart and open sourcing it, but it is part of the creative process to learn from other games, take them apart, find out how to build them, and &lt;strong&gt;THEN&lt;/strong&gt;, introduce a &lt;em&gt;secret sauce&lt;/em&gt; of your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my experience, that is how creativity works, it’s not a magical faucet that you turn on. Staring at a blank page won’t get you anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When stuck for ideas, look to your inspirations, reverse engineer them, and then twist them, play with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love making games because the process of making games is so fun and enriching, and because playing games for research IS fun. Mapping other games' features and design, discovering what makes them special, it's how I get my ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Games, books, movies, culture, the world, the way a plane flies in the air, a dewdrop falling from grass, a conversation at the pub, an overheard diatribe, an article, a boring commute, these are all opportunities to take it all in, and plant the seeds that eventually, suddenly, lead to an outpour of ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exploring the &lt;strong&gt;affordance space&lt;/strong&gt; that you’re creating as you go is like giving birth to a universe of rules and twisting them and changing them as you explore them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give your design doc a scrap and turn things upside down: many ideas will look great written down but once played by humans you might realize they don’t work or they need tweaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always be aware that you can change your idea at any time, tweak it, twist it and give it a spin. You could try understanding how other games make it work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, the only &lt;em&gt;wrong&lt;/em&gt; thing to do is to craft a direct clone and try to pass it off as original. There’s no creative input, it’s the laziest of all processes: the off-brand copy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you embrace, study, and master your inspirations, whether it’s game mechanics or prose or game genres or &lt;em&gt;potato waffle&lt;/em&gt; recipes, you'll just feel free to create, without fearing that its original or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's definitely what happened to me. I proudly embrace the influences of Hotline Miami and Towerfall in the making of &lt;strong&gt;Gunkatana&lt;/strong&gt;, my cyberpunk top down local multiplayer game with single player campaign to boot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Nobody ever became a writer just by wanting to be one. If you have anything to say, anything you feel nobody has ever said before, you have got to feel it so desperately that you will find some way to say it that nobody has ever found before, so that the thing you have to say and the way of saying it blend as one matter — as indissolubly as if they were conceived together."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-F. Scott Fitzgerald&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>